<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 19:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Editing and Version Histories</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-editing-and-version-histories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 19:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-editing-and-version-histories/</guid>
      <description>I would like to start editing the posts that I&amp;rsquo;ve got on the site now. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose any information about what they are/were like in their original state. So I think I need to use and understand git at this point.
For context, I haven&amp;rsquo;t initiated git on this project yet. And I definitely haven&amp;rsquo;t pushed anything to github. And I&amp;rsquo;m even farther away from publishing anything&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Posts</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-first-posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-first-posting/</guid>
      <description>Finally I&amp;rsquo;ll get to the point where I can add these blog posts to the blog. I am expecting this step to be very gratifying. I am also expecting it to include lots of reformatting, because I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing all of this stuff as plain text and I&amp;rsquo;ll need to make it all into MarkDown. I&amp;rsquo;m excited about MarkDown because it&amp;rsquo;s still so close to plain text, and I think it can be opened as plain text (and all of this because I liked Derek Sivers point about writing in plain text), but MarkDown will have some formatting options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flesh on the bones</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-flesh-on-the-bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-flesh-on-the-bones/</guid>
      <description>9:12am
The next bit of the process is still about the basics, but it&amp;rsquo;s about putting more flesh on the bones of the website.
Somehow it&amp;rsquo;s important to me that I can imagine this is all getting set up in a way that will allow more growth in the future. I imagine eventually I&amp;rsquo;ll be wanting to do and learn things about computer life that will go way beyond a static website &amp;ndash; like learning new languages, or going through the Teach Yourself CS series, or building a habit tracker app, or building the amino acid app for Irene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>Is what I am doing a version of &amp;ldquo;Literate Programming?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, but I am interested in learning more about that and what it&amp;rsquo;s relationship might be to documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skeleton from Scratch</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-hugo-skeleton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 05:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-23-hugo-skeleton/</guid>
      <description>5:39am
If I do the quickstart instructions from the Hugo page, I end up with a site that is visible on the localhost immediately. So that means the file system it initializes is &amp;lsquo;complete&amp;rsquo; in some sense of the word.
On the other hand, if I initialize my own site, the file system skeleton is there, but it&amp;rsquo;s relatively empty, and nothing is visible on local host immediately. &amp;ldquo;No page found&amp;rdquo; when I start the development server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Enough to Document</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-22-documentation-principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-22-documentation-principle/</guid>
      <description>4:40pm
One principle I&amp;rsquo;d like to follow is to never go faster than I can document. I have already hit a point with the hugo thing where I can feel myself wanting to speed through something.
I want to do a post about what happens when I do the quicksite start through the hugo website compared to What happens when I initialize a site totally from scratch
What files do I end up with in each case?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Hugo</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-22-setting-up-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-22-setting-up-hugo/</guid>
      <description>1:15 Starting to set up hugo. First thing I notice when I go to the documentation page is that the first thing they mention in their overview is &amp;ldquo;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Security Model&amp;rdquo;. Why is security the first thing?
&amp;ldquo;When developing and building your site, the runtime is the hugo executable. Securing a runtime can be a real challenge.&amp;rdquo;
What is a runtime? A runtime is when the program runs. In the case of Hugo, it&amp;rsquo;s when Hugo builds the website&amp;hellip; it makes the static HTML output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do I start?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-21-where-do-i-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 04:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-21-where-do-i-start/</guid>
      <description>4:45pm With a little more poking around on the internet, I found a LinkedIn group for Technical Writers. The first post I found interesting was asking about learning API documentation, which I intuited is a special subset of technical writing. The author of the post mentioned two things they were already using to learn, and one of them was a website called idratherbewriting.com. Seems like as good a place to start as any, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been poking around on that website for an hour or two now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waking Up</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-21-waking-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2023-02-21-waking-up/</guid>
      <description>Man, just deleted a bunch of stuff I wrote here.
The gist was, tell the story of the first post to this as yet unsubstantiated blog.
Tell it with some details related to waking up in the middle of the night, getting tempted by a linkedIn thing from Sergei&amp;hellip; Why is he posting a code challenge think? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he have a job already? Yep, he works for some company that Jeff Bezos started?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Lower power is the spirit of the depths.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
